<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>

	<name>[RF] Fishing [1.1]</name>
	<author>Rainbeau Flambe</author>
	<url>https://github.com/firefoxpdm/Rainbeau-s-Fishing</url>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.1</li>
		<li>1.2</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<loadBefore>
		<li>VanillaExpanded.VFEProduction</li>
	</loadBefore>

	<description>(Last update: 2020-03-11)

Originally from https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php?topic=46165

This mod gives pawns the ability to catch and cook fish.

It's possible to create "fishing spots" adjacent to water, where pawns can catch fish. It's also possible to build "shellfish traps" that might net you shellfish, shrimp, snails or small fish. And your pawns can now prepare sushi and various other seafood dishes.

(Is it ironic that this mod was created by someone who finds fishing to be mind-numbingly dull, and who hates seafood in any form? I think it's a bit ironic.)

- Rainbeau Flambe (dburgdorf)

=====

How Fishing Works:

Fishing is a custom work type, which relies on the "Animals" skill. Pawns with higher skill will fish faster, and have a higher chance of successfully catching something. (Additionally, fishing serves as a joy activity for pawns with a passion for the Animals skill.) Fishing spots can become depleted if overfished, and so will occasionally need to be allowed to "recharge."

Fish and eels can be caught at any fishing spot, though the type of fish available varies with the biome, and eels are more common in marshes than in water tiles. Squid can only be caught in ocean tiles.

Shellfish traps will periodically catch shellfish or tiny fish automatically, without any pawn interaction. They will sometimes take a bit of damage in doing so, though, and will thus occasionally need to be repaired.

Fish and shellfish can be cleaned (butchered) for meat, while squid and eels can be butchered for both meat and leather.

The mod also adds ice fishing spots, which work as normal fishing spots, except that they can only be constructed on frozen river or lake water tiles generated by my own "Permafrost" mod, Fumblesneeze's "Ice," or "Nature's Pretty Sweet." Note that ice fishing spots cannot be placed on vanilla ice tiles, and will appear on the "Production" tab of the Architect menu only if at least one of the "freezing" mods is actually in your mod list.

=====

Compatibility:

If you try to remove "Fishing" from a game in progress, you will very likely make the map unplayable, at least if your pawns have actually caught any fish and/or made any seafood dishes.

Apparently, this mod conflicts with "Thanks for All the Fish," which doesn't really surprise me, as the two mods do many of the same things, albeit in different ways. I may eventually see about trying to make them compatible, but frankly, I'm not sure I see why anyone would need to use two different fishing mods at the same time, anyway.

"Fishing" shouldn't conflict with any other mods.

=====

Credits:

Most of the fish graphics were provided to me by Steam user Draegon.

The ability to fish from bridges draws both conceptually and specifically from Rikiki's "FishIndustry" mod, though what I've done here is less elaborate than, and over time has diverged rather significantly from, what's he's done in that mod.

The traditional Chinese language files were provided by Steam user Alane. The simplified Chinese language translation files were provided by Steam user kghostSATORI. The Japanese language files were provided by Proxyer.

=====

License:

If you're a modpack maker and want to include this mod in your pack, or if you're a modder and want to use it as the basis of a derivative mod, please feel free to do so. I ask only that you let me know about it. 

=====

If you have any (helpful) suggestions for improvement, please let me know!

	</description>

</ModMetaData>
